MOHAMAD ALMEARI

FULL STACK WFB DEVELOPER

mohamet.almeari@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with 1+ years of experience and a Master's degree in Civil Engineering. Specialized in React, Rails and SEO optimizing with a focus on clean code and accessibility. Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver projects on time, resulting in a 90% project success rate. Actively participated in code reviews, resulting in a 40% improvement in code quality.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, ¡Query, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Mobile/Responsive Development, Jest, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, RESTful API

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

Feb, 2023 - Present

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including React, Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building 20+ full-stack projects independently and via pair-programming. Some of them are listed below:

i-Share — Born from a passion for photography and storytelling, it's a vibrant community platform where photo enthusiasts worldwide connect over shared interests. Users can upload their most captivating photos, discover stories from across the globe, and engage in lively discussions.

• Built with: (Front-end: React, Redux, CSS - Back-end: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL) | GH repo

i-Post — Unleash your creativity by sharing your posts and discovering captivating content from others, it's a dynamic platform where your ideas come to life. Users can create posts on their interesting topics, read posts from others, and interact with the community through likes and comments.

• Built with: (Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, CSS) | GH repo

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)
May, 2023 – Oct, 2023

- Mentored 2+ junior web developers, providing technical support through two meetings every week.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to boost code quality and overall performance, resulting in a 30% decrease in the long-term cost of maintenance and bug fixes.
- Provided advice and tips on maintaining motivation to maintain longevity in the program, enhancing student retention by 20% from the previous curriculum module.

Alburuj Corporation Hybrid

• Led BIM integration, improving project coordination efficiency by 70%, reducing timelines, and minimizing errors.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE Dec, 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

ISTANBUL CULTURE UNIVERSITY

May, 2021

May, 2017 – Aug, 2019

MSc, Structural Engineering

Structural Engineer

- Thesis: "A Proposed Model for Estimating the Curvature Ductility of RC Sections"
- Developed software using VB.net for analyzing Moment-Curvature and Interaction Curves in RC sections, enhancing ductility for structures to meet performance requirements under various loading conditions.

ARAB INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

May, 2017

BEng, Civil Engineering

- Specialization in Structural Engineering
- Consistently ranked among the top 4 students for seven semesters.